sleeptrain.com 2017-06-09

# Privacy Policy

**Last Updated: June 16, 2016**

At Sleep Train we are committed to ensuring the privacy of our customers. This privacy policy explains Sleep Train’s privacy practices, including those of our Web site located at www.sleeptrain.com (“Site”), for our customers who purchase our products and services. The Site is owned and operated by The Sleep Train, Inc., a wholly owned subsidiary of Mattress Firm, Inc.  By using our Site, you consent to the terms of this privacy policy

This policy does not apply to the Customer Ratings and Reviews Terms of Use. Please [click here](http://www.sleeptrain.com/bazaarvoice-terms-conditions.html) to access the Customer Ratings and Reviews Terms of Use.

**What is Personal Information?**

Personal information is information that specifically identifies an individual such as a customer’s name, address, telephone number, e–mail address, credit card or other account number, and information about that individual’s activities when directly linked to that person, such as information about his or her purchases. Personal information also includes demographic information such as date of birth, gender, geographic area and preferences when such information is linked to other personal information that identifies you.

Personal information does not include “aggregate” information. Aggregate information is data we collect about a group or category of products, services or customers, from which individual customer identities have been removed. In other words, information about how you use a service may be collected and combined with information about how others use the same service, but no personal information will be included in the resulting data. Likewise, information about the products you purchase may be collected and combined with information about the products purchased by others. Aggregate data helps us understand trends and customer needs so that we can better consider new products and services, and tailor existing products and services to customer desires.

**Personal Information We Collect**

You provide personal information to us in a number of ways when you visit our Site. For example, you provide us with personal information when you: (1) purchase products and services, (2) create an user account, (3) sign up for our email list or electronic newsletters, (3) participate in surveys, sweepstakes, and promotions, (4) create a wish list, (5) elect to share content from this website with your friends,(6) register on our site and create an account using already established social networking accounts such as Facebook and Twitter, (7) submit a warranty registration, and (8) contact us by email for any reason (such as to request customer service or provide us with your comments/feedback). We collect your name, billing and shipping addresses, email address, friend's email address, phone number, fax number, credit card information, login information, order information, wish list, and payment settings in this manner. We also collect personal information from you if you submit an online job application or resume to us, including your name and email address, as well as other employment related information that you provide to us at your option.

**How We Use Personal Information**

In general, we use personal information to process your requests or transactions and provide you with high-quality products and services or to inform you about other products or services we think will be of interest. For example, we use your information to deliver products or provide services you have purchased and to send you marketing communications regarding products, services, surveys and promotions. For example, we may use your personal and non-personal information to: 1) fulfill your requests for products and services; 2) provide you with targeted offers and advertising; 3) contact you with information and promotional materials and offers from Sleep Train as well as from our subsidiaries, affiliates, marketing partners, advertisers and other third parties; 4) contact you if there is a problem with your order; 5) ask you to review your in-store experience; 6) review Site usage and operations; 7) conduct marketing research and/or analysis in order to optimize our search engine marketing strategies; and 8) verify or supplement your personal information with information from third party sources in order to guard against fraud. When we use personal information in our internal marketing efforts, we provide you with choices (See Choice below) and do not disclose the information to third parties except as described in this privacy policy. We may also receive information from third parties with whom we have business relationships, and will combine this information with the other personal information we maintain about you. In such cases, this privacy policy governs this information.

Pixel tags on our site may be used to collect information about your visit, including the pages you view, the features you use, the links you click, and other actions you take in connection with the site.  This information may include your computer's IP address, your browser type, your operating system, date and time information, and other technical information about your computer.  We may also track certain information about the identity of the website you visited immediately before coming to our site. . 

Pixel tags and cookies in our emails to you may be used to track your interactions with those messages, such as when you receive, open, or click a link in an email message from us

We also work with business partners that use tracking technologies to deliver advertisements on our behalf across the Internet.  These companies may collect information about your visits to our site and your interaction with our advertising and other communications.

We may combine the information we collect through cookies and pixel tags with other information we have collected from you. This information may be used to improve our website, to personalize your online experience, to help us deliver information to you, to determine the effectiveness of our advertising, and for other internal business purposes.

**Sharing of Personal Information**

We do not sell, rent or share personal information with third parties without your prior consent except in the limited circumstances described in this privacy policy. We share personal information with third-party vendors who assist us in performing internal functions necessary to operate our business. These functions may include, for example, distributing emails, managing a database of customer information, providing fraud prevention, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments and fulfilling/delivering orders. We require our third party vendors to keep such information confidential and to only use the information for the purpose it was provided. We are not responsible for any additional information you provide directly to these parties, and we encourage you to become familiar with their practices before disclosing information directly to them.

We also disclose personal information when we believe it is appropriate to comply with the law (e.g., a lawful subpoena, warrant or court order); to enforce or apply this privacy policy or our other policies or agreements; to initiate, render, bill, and collect for amounts owed to us; to protect our or our customers´ rights, property or safety; to protect our customers from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful use of our Site; or if we reasonably believe that an emergency involving immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to any person requires disclosure of communications or justifies disclosure of records without delay.

In addition, information about our customers, including personally identifiable information, may be disclosed as part of any merger, acquisition, debt financing, sale of company assets, as well as in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership in which personally identifiable information could be transferred to third parties as one of the business assets of the company.

**Cookies, Web Beacons, and Other Similar Technologies**

Our website uses "cookie" and "web beacon" technology. We use cookies and web beacons to identify your device, provide website user authentication, conduct fraud prevention and management services, distinguish you from other visitors, record your IP address and operating system, understand your use of our site, determine the address of a referring website and determine the time and date of your visit.  This information is used for fulfilling contracts with our business partners, and to help us serve you better by improving our website design as well as our products, services, and promotions. We do not otherwise track any information about your use of other websites.

A cookie is a small data file that is placed on the hard drive of your computer when you visit a website. A "session cookie" expires immediately when you end your session (i.e., close your browser). A "persistent cookie" stores information on the hard drive so when you end your session and return to the same website at a later date, the cookie information is still available. When you visit our website, we may use both a session and a persistent cookie. These cookies may contain information (such as a unique user ID) that is used to track your usage of our website and in some cases, your e-mail address. Your e-mail address is only saved in this cookie if you register with us.

If you register with us, this cookie allows us to recognize you when you return to our website and provides you with access to your account information. If you save your information with or order from us, we may also use cookies to monitor and maintain information about your use of our website. If you have not saved your information with or ordered from us, we may monitor and maintain information about your use of our website in a manner that does not identify you. You can disable cookies at any time by using your browser options; however, if you turn off cookies, we will not be able to track your order or enable you to make a purchase from our website. In addition, we will not be able to recognize you as a registered user to allow you access to your account information.

A web beacon is a small string of code that represents a clear graphic image and is used in conjunction with a cookie.  A web beacon allows us to capture certain additional types of information about a visitor's actions on a web site, such as a visitor's cookie number, the time, date, duration and number of page views, a description of the page where the Web beacon is placed, and details about any items that were purchased.  Web beacons help us analyze our customers' online behavior and measure the effectiveness of our website and our advertising.  We work with service providers that help us track, collect and analyze this information.

**Third Party Advertising Partners**

We use third-party service providers to serve advertisements (banners or links) on our behalf across the Internet.

These advertising service providers may collect non-identifiable information about your visits to our website, and your interactions with our products and services. Such non-identifiable information does not include your name, address, e-mail address or other personal information. The information is collected through the use of cookies and pixel tags (also known as action tags), which is industry-standard technology used by most major websites.

In addition to the information about your visits to our website, our service providers may also use the information about your visits to other websites to target advertisements for products and services available from Sleep Train.

Currently, we use third party-placed tracking pixels and cookies from the following advertising delivery partners: TruEffect, Amazon and Google. In the future we may partner with other companies to provide interest-based advertising, both on and off sleeptrain.com. If this occurs, Sleep Train provides you with an opportunity to opt out when these advertisements are served. You may manage your third-party advertising preferences by clicking on the links below:

  * **[I would like to opt OUT of Google Analytics Display Advertising.](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/)**

If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices for not having this information used by third-party service providers, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

**Facebook Custom Audience Ads**

We may display interest-based ads to you when you are using Facebook through a tool offered by Facebook called the Custom Audience Tool. This tool allows us to personalize our ads based on your shopping experience with us. We do not share any of your personal information, including your shopping history, with Facebook. The tool lets Sleep Train convert your email address to a unique number that Facebook uses to match to unique numbers Facebook generates from email addresses of its users.

**Email Marketing**

If you are opted in to receive marketing emails from us and wish to unsubscribe, you can do so by clicking on the Unsubscribe hyperlink at the bottom of the marketing email you receive. We will note in our database that you have elected to opt out of future emails from our company. Your record will still remain in our database but you will not receive any future mailings unless we manually opt you back in. 

You may also choose to opt out of emails by sending an email to us at [customerservice@sleeptrain.com](mailto:customerservice@sleeptrain.com). If you choose to opt out with this method, please be sure to include the email address that you would like us to unsubscribe.

**Links to Other Web Sites**

Our Site contains links to other web sites. Any personal information you provide on the linked pages is provided directly to that third party and is subject to that third party's privacy policy. Except as described above, we are not responsible for the content or privacy and security practices and policies of web sites to which we link. Links from our web site to third parties or to other sites are provided for your convenience. We encourage you to learn about their privacy and security practices and policies before providing them with personal information.

**Use of our Site by Children**

We encourage parents to take an active interest in their children’s use of the Internet. Our site is not meant for children and we do not intend to collect information from children who are under 18 years of age. If you are under 18, you should not provide information on our Site and should ask your parent to do so for you.

**Security**

We have put into place reasonable security measures in an effort to protect personal information while it is under our control. All personal information relating to our customers is stored in a secure environment separate from our Site.

**[Click here to view our complete Security Policy](http://www.sleeptrain.com/security-policy.html).**

**Choice**

We give you the following options to opt-out of receiving communications from us or to request that we correct or delete your personal information: (1) contact our customer service department by phone at 800-919-2337 (2) email us at [customerservice@sleeptrain.com](mailto:customerservice@sleeptrain.com); or (3) write to us at the following address with your request:

**Sleep Train**  
Attn: Digital Manager  
2205 Plaza Drive  
Rocklin, CA 95765

If, in the future, we decide to share personal information with any third parties for their own marketing purposes, we will update this privacy policy to reflect such change and provide you with the opportunity to opt-out of such disclosure of your personal information.

**Policy Changes**

We will periodically modify our Privacy Policy so that it remains relevant and current with changing technologies, applicable laws, evolving business practices, and the needs of our customers. Whenever we modify our privacy policy, we will post the revised policy here, with an updated revision date. If we make material changes to the policy or in how we will use your personal information, we will also notify you by other means, such as sending an email and/or posting a notice on our corporate website and/or social media pages prior to the changes taking effect. We will also keep prior versions of this Privacy Policy in an archive for your review. We encourage you to periodically review the privacy statements for the products and services you use to learn how we are protecting your information. If you continue to use our website after notice of the change has been given, you will be deemed to have accepted such changes.

**Your Comments or Concerns**

We welcome your feedback. If you have any comments or concerns about this privacy policy or would like to contact us for any reason, you may reach a customer service representative via e-mail at [customerservice@sleeptrain.com](mailto:customerservice@sleeptrain.com) or by phone at 1-800-919-2337.
